<?xml version='1.0' ?>
<faqs>
    <section title='Problems Getting Started'>
        <faq id='Cannot unzip'>
            <question>Why can't I unzip the download library?</question>
            <answer>HttpUnit is archived using the classes in the java.util.zip package.
                    Some older Unzip programs cannot understand this format.
                    If you are using WinZip, stick to version 7.0 or later.</answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="org.xml.sax">
            <question>What is the org.xml.sax package?</question>
            <answer>You may be getting compile or runtime errors asking for the org.xml.sax package.
                    You need to have xerces or another XML parser in your classpath. Xerces is included in the download.</answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="api-help">
            <question>I don't understand how the ... API works.</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[The best way to understand how the API works is to look at the samples in the <tt>test</tt> directory.
                     This contains an example of just about every feature of the library and is used to verify that they continue to work.
                     Of course, if you know a tech writer who would like to contribute to improving the documentation, that is always welcome :)]]></answer>
        </faq>
    </section>

    <section title="Server Issues">
        <faq>
            <question>Is https supported?</question>
            <url>sslfaq.html</url>
        </faq>
        <faq id="proxy">
            <question>Can I use HttpUnit through a proxy server?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[Yes. Call <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/WebClient.html#setProxyServer(java.lang.String, int)">
                    <code>WebClient.setProxyServer( host, port )</code></a>before sending your request.]]></answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="masquerade">
            <question>How can I handle certificates from a test machine?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[Often you will need to run your secure website - complete with certificates - from a test
                    server. Under most conditions, this will cause a validation problem, as the JSSE detects that the
                    certificate does not match the requested server. You can "trick" HttpUnit into accepting the certificate
                    as follows:<p>
                    Assume that your certificate is for your real machine at <code>realserver.domain.com</code> and your
                    test machine is at the IP address: 192.168.1.23. You want your tests to send requests to
                    <code>realserver.domain.com</code> (since that is what your certificates expect), but to actually
                    go to the test machine.<p>
                    First, create a <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/DNSListener.html"><code>DNSListener</code></a>:
                    <pre>DNSListener aListener = <b>new</b> DNSListener() {
    <b>public</b> String getIpAddress( String hostName ) {
        if (hostName.equals( "realserver.domain.com" )) <b>return</b> "192.168.1.23";
        <b>return</b> hostName;
    }
};</pre>This listener substitutes the test IP address for the specified server name. Now specify this listener
                    for your client by calling
                    <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/ClientProperties.html#setDnsListener(com.meterware.httpunit.DNSListener)">
                    <code>wc.getClientProperties().setDnsListener( aListener )</code></a>.
                    All subsequent requests will be rerouted as you specify, but the security layer should think it is coming
                    from the named server.]]></answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="charset">
            <question>Why isn't HttpUnit handling my non-English pages?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[When no Content-Type header is specified, HTML 1.1 says that the character set is to be taken as iso-8859-1.
                    Unfortunately, some HTTP servers do not send this parameter correctly, and many browsers provide a workaround
                    to permit the user to determine the character set in some other fashion.  To imitate this behavior,
                    HttpUnit allows you to set the expected character set for future pages by calling
                    <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/HttpUnitOptions.html#setDefaultCharacterSet(java.lang.String)"><code>HttpUnitOptions.setDefaultCharacterSet()</code></a>.
                    This setting will not apply to those pages for which the server specifies the character set.</p>
                    <p>Non-English form handling is supported as well. Any parameter values entered into a form will be encoded as the same
                    character set as the document containing the form. The server code will then have to handle those characters
                    appropriately. In Java, that would be converting them to Unicode with statements such as
                    <pre>String rawName = request.getParameter( "name" );
String japaneseName = <b>new</b> String( name.getBytes("8859_1"), "EUC_JP" );</pre>
                    where the proper encoding should be substituted for "EUC_JP". The <code>getBytes</code> call is needed to extract
                    the raw bytes from the parameter string.]]></answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="timeout">
            <question>How does HttpUnit handle request timeouts?</question>
            <answer>Badly. Unfortunately, through JDK 1.3, HttpURLConnection (used by HttpUnit to access web servers) has no support for timeouts.
                    Supposedly, this is changed in JDK 1.4, but HttpUnit does not support the new feature as yet.</answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="rejected cookies">
            <question>Why isn't HttpUnit seeing cookies from my site?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[According to the <a href="http://www.faqs.org/rfcs/rfc2965.html">Cookie specification</a>,
                    sites may specify a domain and path to restrict the scope of their cookies. These specifications
                    must follow certain rules, and the vast majority of sites do. Unfortunately, there are some
                    popular sites (such as Yahoo.com) which do not. By default, HttpUnit is very strict about
                    implementing the spec, and will reject such cookies. You can control this behavior by calls to the
                    <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/cookies/CookieProperties.html">CookieProperties</a> class.
                    If you suspect that this is happening, you can also register a
                    <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/cookies/CookieListener.html">CookieListener</a> to watch for cookies
                    being rejected.]]></answer>
        </faq>
    </section>

    <section title="Form Handling Problems">
        <faq id="uncheck">
            <question>How do I uncheck a checkbox?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[The setParameter call lets you specify the values per parameter name. An unchecked checkbox has no value to transmit, so you would call:
                    <pre><code>    form.setParameter( "checkbox-name", new String[0] );</code></pre> or
                    <pre><code>    form.removeParameter( "checkbox-name" );</code></pre>
                    If the checkbox's name is unique, you can say:
                    <pre><code>    form.setCheckbox( "checkbox-name", false );</code></pre> or
                    <pre><code>    form.toggleCheckbox( "checkbox-name" );</code></pre>]]></answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="hidden">
            <question>Why can't I change hidden parameter values?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[HttpUnit is intended primarily to imitate what a user could do. Since a user cannot change
                    hidden parameters directly, HttpUnit stops you from doing it in your code as part of its validation
                    of parameters against the form containing them. If you have to change these values, you have a couple of choices:
                    <ul><li>Rather than setting the parameters directly on the form, call
                    <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/WebForm.html#newUnvalidatedRequest()">
                    <code>WebForm.newUnvalidatedRequest()</code></a>
                    (specifying any submit button information if necessary) to obtain a <tt>WebRequest</tt> copied from
                    the form but not tied to it. You will then be able to set any values you like in this request.
                    Note that parameter order is not guaranteed when such a request is submitted, nor are any JavaScript events fired.</li>
                    <li>You can call <code>&lt;form&gt;.getScriptableObject().setParameterValue( &lt;name&gt;, &lt;value&gt; );</code> to change
                    the underlying value in the form. This will behave the way JavaScript does - resetting the form will now restore this value,
                    rather than the original one.</li></ul>]]></answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="button click">
            <question>How do I get the response when I click a button?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[When you call Button.click, a number of things can happen, depending on the definition of the button.
                    Unfortunately, it is then impossible to predict what, if any, response is relevant. The method therefore
                    does not return WebResponse. In most cases, it is the main window of your browser that you care about
                    and you can always obtain that by calling
                    <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/WebClient.html#getCurrentPage()"><code>client.getCurrentPage()</code></a>.]]></answer>
        </faq>
    </section>

    <section title="JavaScript support">
        <faq id="javascript">
            <question>How do I use HttpUnit to test my pages that use JavaScript?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[For most purposes, You should not have to do anything special; however, not all JavaScript constructs are supported as yet.
                    See <a href="javascript-support.html">the list of supported JavaScript features</a> for more information.]]></answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="norhino">
            <question>JavaScript is not being executed at all. Why not?</question>
            <answer>If you do not have the Rhino JAR (js.jar) in your classpath, JavaScript features do not work.</answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="disable scripting">
            <question>How do I turn off scripting for certain tests?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[If you call <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/HttpUnitOptions.html#setScriptingEnabled(boolean)"><code>HttpUnitOptions.setScriptingEnabled( false );</code></a>
                    JavaScript will not be interpreted.]]></answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="nofunction">
            <question>My JavaScript works in a browser, but HttpUnit says "ReferenceError: ... is not defined"</question>
            <answer>This usually indicates that you are calling a function which contains statements that HttpUnit does not understand.
                    Rhino unfortunately does not provide a very helpful error message in such cases. Try removing statements from the
                    function until you find out which one is causing the problem and then submit a request for the offending construct to be supported.</answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="unsupported">
            <question>How do I handle a page that uses JavaScript features that HttpUnit does not support?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[If you call
                    <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/HttpUnitOptions.html#setExceptionsThrownOnScriptError(boolean)">
                        <code>HttpUnitOptions.setExceptionsThrownOnScriptError( false );</code></a>
                    problems will be recorded but will not throw exceptions. You can see the list of problems detected by calling
                    <a href="api/com/meterware/httpunit/HttpUnitOptions.html#getScriptErrorMessages()">
                        <code>HttpUnitOptions.getScriptErrorMessages();</code>
                    </a>]]></answer>
        </faq>
        <faq id="text">
            <question>I called document.write() in my page, but getText() does not show the results! Why not?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[The execution of scripts only affects the parsed result. WebResponse.getText() shows the <i>original</i>
                    text in the page. You will see the changed text only if you examine text inside a parsed item such as a form, link, or table.]]></answer>
        </faq>
    </section>

    <section title="ServletUnit usage">
        <faq id="session">
            <question>How can I see the servlet session between calls?</question>
            <answer><![CDATA[Servlet session is maintained on the server. Therefore, if you want to do this, you must be using
                    <a href="servletunit-intro.html">ServletUnit</a>.
                    Once you have that working, you can get take advantage of the power of ServletUnit to get at internal values,
                    using the <a href="api/com/meterware/servletunit/InvocationContext.html"><code>InvocationContext</code></a> object. For example,
<pre><code>
ServletUnitClient client = ...          // the client you have been using
client.getResponse( servlet-url );      // invoke your servlet normally

// now get an invocation context using the <i>same</i> URL used to invoke the servlet
InvocationContext ic = client.newInvocationContext( servlet-url );
// obain the session just used. Note: pass false to avoid creating it if it does not already exist
HttpSession session = ic.getRequest().getSession( false );</code></pre>

Now you can examine the contents of the session to see what the servlet left in it.]]></answer>
        </faq>

        <faq id="JSP">
            <question>Can I use JSPs with ServletUnit?</question>
            <answer>Absolutely! But since you are now emulating the servlet environment, you will need to make sure that you have access
                    to the relevant classes. By default, ServletUnit is configured to use Jasper, the JSP engine which is part of Tomcat.
                    You will therefore need the Jasper jar in your classpath, along with any on which it depends.  Once you have done that,
                    your JSPs should run, just as they would in Tomcat.</answer>
        </faq>

    </section>
</faqs>



